Alex Clark



About

Alex Clark is a **Python Web Developer** from Baltimore, Maryland, USA living in Bethesda, Maryland. He has a **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** from Loyola University in Maryland and has worked as a **Network Engineer, Software Engineer, Systems Administrator** and **Technical Team Leader** since May, 1998. He is also the **President of DC Python**, a non-profit organization he co-founded to promote and support the use of Python software in DC.

Skills

Web Development	Python	Systems	Networking
• HTML	• Django	Apple macOS Unix	• TCP/IP
• CSS	Pyramid	Ubuntu Linux	• CIFS
JavaScript	• Plone	CentOS Linux	• NFS
	• Zope	Microsoft Windows	• DNS

Profiles

GitHub | Twitter

Work Experience

ACLARK.NET, LLC

Partner & Python Web Developer

May, 2004 — Present

http://aclark.net

• Develop and deploy, support and maintain Python web applications with Django, Plone, Pyramid and Zope and related technologies e.g. HTML/CSS/JavaScript.

Neurophysiology Imaging Facility (NIF) \rightarrow Division of Intramural Research Programs (DIRP) \rightarrow National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) \rightarrow National Institutes of Health (NIH)

Systems Administrator

March, 2013 — Present

http://www.nimh.nih.gov/labs-at-nimh/research-areas/research-support-services

- Evaluate and recommend hardware and software for purchase by NIF
- Install, configure and maintain hardware and software. Troubleshoot and resolve hardware and software problems
- Install, configure and maintain operating systems, web server, content management system, FTP server, directory services, file sharing services, revision control system, and backups Manage network and system security. Analyze network performance and access to public resources
- Provide desktop support to NIF staff, resolve productivity issues
- Provide liaison to NIH CIT on infrastructure and security related issues

Scientific and Statistical Computing Core (SSCC) \rightarrow Division of Intramural Research Programs (DIRP) \rightarrow National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) \rightarrow National Institutes of Health (NIH)

May, 2002 — October, 2005

Systems Administrator

http://www.nimh.nih.gov/labs-at-nimh/research-areas/research-support-services

- Evaluate and recommend hardware for purchase by SSCC
- Install, configure and maintain hardware. Troubleshoot and resolve hardware problems
- Install, configure and maintain operating systems, web server, content management system, FTP server, directory services, file sharing services, revision control system, and tape backups Manage network and system security. Analyze network performance and access to public resources
- Provide desktop support to SSCC members, resolved productivity issues
- Provide liaison to NIH CIT on infrastructure and security related issues
- Manage content management system, provide instruction to SSCC members on how to add and edit content
- Design and implement new site technology
- Respond to and resolve web site issues for the SSCC and AFNI community

Genuity

Network Engineer

October, 1998 — November, 2001

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BBN_Technologies

- Developed Perl and Expect software to support remote configuration of over 2,000 Cisco 2511 Access Servers, Equinox Terminal Servers, and Cisco Catalyst 1900/2820 Ethernet Switches.
- Developed Perl CGI software to support remote configuration of access servers with over 4 ingress T1 data lines via SNMP e.g. Cisco 5400, Lucent APX 8000, Nortel CVX 1800.
- Configured over 2,000 Cisco Access Servers, Equinox Terminal Servers and Cisco Catalyst Ethernet Switches.

- Installed and configured Debian Linux, Redhat Linux, Sun Microsystems Solaris Unix and Microsoft Windows workstations and servers.
- Configured Linux kernel to support myriad network interface cards.
- Researched and resolved complex network connectivity issues.
- Verified successful negotiation of TCP, PPP and L2TP protocols through dial-up connections between client programs and remote access servers.
- Performed maintenance on AOLNet and DialLinx dial-up networks.
- Provided production operations support.

Charm Net

Systems Administrator

January, 1998 — August, 1998

http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20070125005632/en/DataPoint-Acquires-Award-Winning-Charm-Net

- Managed 4 BSDI Unix servers for over 2,000 users.
- Installed and configured DNS, NFS, Sendmail, Apache, INND and Dump/Restore.
- Installed and configured hardware and software for streaming FM radio to the internet.
- Installed and configured BSDI Unix servers and Microsoft Windows workstations and servers.
- Provided production operations support.

Loyola University Maryland

Help Desk Consultant & Student Technician

August, 1996 — November, 1997

http://www.loyola.edu/department/technology-services

- Provided telephone and in-person technical support to students, faculty, and administrators.
- Performed installation, maintenance, and trouble-shooting of hardware and software in labs, offices, and dormitories.
- Installed and configured Sun Microsystems Solaris Unix, Slackware Linux, Redhat Linux and Microsoft Windows workstations and servers.
- Provided production operations support.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Loyola University Maryland

January, 1999

http://www.loyola.edu/academics/computer-science

Volunteer

DC Python

Co-Founder & President

2008 — Present

http://dcpython.org

• Co-founded 501(c)(3) non-profit organization to promote & support Python software in DC.

Pillow

Fork Author & Project Leader

July, 2010 — Present

http://python-pillow.org

- Forked popular Python Imaging Library (PIL) software to create frequently-updated and well-maintained version.
- Foster growth of core development team from single member to five members over five years.
- Write and submit grant proposal to fund Python 3 compatible version of Pillow; sent to Python Software Foundation February 28, 2013; passed unanimously on March 4, 2013.
- Implement and manage quarterly release schedule.
- Continuously oversee development to ensure best possible quality of releases.

Publications

Plone 3.3 Site Administration

PACKT Publishing Limited

July, 2010

https://www.packtpub.com/web-development/plone-33-site-administration

"Manage your site like a Plone professional."